Jiaxin Li

Summary

- Mobile Development resource with over 5 years of experience in developing iOS and Android applications.
- Currently pursuing Master of Science in Computer Science and possesses a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and a Minor in Business Administration.
- Extensive experience with Objective-C and Swift programming technologies as well as dynamic data and interfaces such as XML, JSON, and RESTful APIs.
- Well-versed in working with MySQL and MS SQL Server as well as Web Servers such as Apache, Tom Cat, and Azure.
- Motivated temperament with excellent verbal and written communication skills and the ability to collaborate with team members and take ownership of tasks and work.

Technical Skills

Operating Systems: Windows Vista/7/XP, Linux (Ubuntu), Mac OS

Development Environments: Visual Studio, Eclipse, MATLAB, XCode, Android Studio, Anaconda, Brackets,

WebStorm

Development Languages: Java, C#, C++, Objective C, C, Swift, Assembly, Ruby, Python, Shell Script, Kotlin

Web Development: HTML/CSS, JSP, PHP, .NET, JavaScript, Python, Java Spring

Server-side Integration: Ruby on Rails, Java Spring, Python **Database:** MySQL, MS SQL Server, MS Access, DynamoDB, RDS

Web Server: Apache, Tom Cat, Azure

Cloud Computing: AWS S3, EC2, Lambda, API Gateway, Cognito, Heroku, PinPoint, Amplify, Device Farm

Virtualization: VMware, VirtualBox **Hardware Integration:** BLE 4.2, iBeacon

Al/Machine Learning: Sci-kit Learn, TensorFlow, Deep Neural Network

Professional Experience

SPS, LLC April 2018 – Present

Chief Executive Officer & Co-Founder

- Overseeing business operations which include product development & design, financial, legal and admin.
- Working with off-shore vendors to efficiently manage product transportations and quality control.

The Thrifty Hipster, LLC

November 2017 - Present

iOS Software Engineer (Part-time)

- Development of the iOS application "Craft Notes" using Swift, SwiftyJSON, Alamofire, FirebaseUI, JSON, RESTful Apis, currently available in the AppStore.
- Maintained the iOS application "Craft Notes" with its' backend service hosted on Heroku.

FailSafe, LLC

April 2017 - November 2018

Chief Operations Officer & Co-Founder

- Overseeing business operations which include product development & design, financial, legal and admin
- Co-founded and developed the early-stage business concepts and strategies.
- Developed the iOS application "SaveSafe", which is served as a smart control interface of "SaveSafe" using Swift, JSON, XML, RESTful APIs and Bluetooth Low Energy.

Developed the Android application "SaveSafe", which is served as a smart control interface of "SaveSafe" using Java, Kotlin, JSON, XML and RESTful APIs.

Object Partners November 2017 – May 2018

Senior Consultant (Mobile Development)

- Maintained and developed the iOS application entitled "Radisson Rewards" for a hotel client using Objective-C, Swift, JSON, XML, Hybrid UI, Java Script, Bootstrap and encryption.
- Supported and developed the Android application entitled "Radisson Rewards" for a hotel client using Java, Kotlin, JSON, XML, Hybrid UI, Java Script, Bootstrap and encryption.
- Successfully finalized the major brand transition from Club Carlson to Radisson Rewards which included images, texts, icons and application structure.
- Successfully completed the major application structure change to adopt the new domain name change.

BookMobile June 2017 – November 2017

Mobile Developer (Part-time)

- Maintained and developed15 iOS meditation applications using RESTful APIs, Objective-C, Swift and Hybrid UI.
- Maintained and developed 15 Android meditation applications using RESTful APIs, Java and Hybrid UI.
- Developed a new iOS application entitled "Tending Dandelions" using Swift, RESTful APIs and Hybrid UI.

The Thrifty Hipster, LLC May 2017
Consultant

• Implemented updates and bug fixes to the iOS application entitled "Happy Hour Now", currently available in the AppStore.

Brandography.com, LLC April 2017

Consultant

• Implemented updates and bug fixes to the iOS and Android application entitled "Idle Free Service", currently available in the AppStore and Google Play.

Divi, LLC July 2015 – April 2017

iOS Software Engineer

- Maintained and developed the iOS and Android application entitled "Divi Up" using Objective-C and Swift, currently available in the AppStore and Google Play.
- Maintained and developed the backend Content Management System using Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and HTML 5.
- Used Agile methodology for work organization.
- Participated in meetings to define and enhance user experience and user interface.
- Provided production support to ensure users' satisfaction.
- Utilized REST API for data exchange from the server.

EHANG, Inc Summer 2014

Software Engineer Intern

- Developed IOS software, entitled Ghost Drone, to control the Unmanned Aerial Vehicle named Ghost as a team of two software developers, currently available in the AppStore.
- Finalized Android software, entitled Ghost Drone to control the Unmanned Aerial Vehicle named Ghost with a team of six software developers, currently available in the Google Play.

- Focused on UI design (Cocoa) and data exchange of the embedded devices.
- Wrote microprocessor program using Assembly Language.
- Worked well independently, as well as in a team.
- Enhanced communication and analytical skills with weekly meetings and technical document.

IR Internet Resort Pte. Ltd.

2012

Front Desk Staff/Technician (Part-time)

- Strengthened customer service skills by interacting with a wide customer demographic while ensuring satisfactions.
- Resolved up to 20 daily hardware, software and network issues.
- Implemented server and Point of Sale system with MySQL database.
- Improved verbal communication skills and problem-solving skills.

Interactive Digital Center Asia

April – September 2011

Project Leader & Research Engineer Intern

- Developed MATLAB Program and embedded device for video system to glass-free 3D display as the project leader of a group of 3 software developers.
- Built frame on Samsung display for glass-free 3D.
- Created image depth using RGB color definition.
- Performed well under pressure, while adhering to tight project turnaround timelines.
- Gained creative thinking skills and leadership as the project leader.

Temasek Polytechnic

Spring 2011

Student Assistant Web Developer

- Integrated school website with JSP and HTML language.
- Developed physical RJ45 wire plant solution.
- Improved professional communication skills in academic and work environments.
- Built strong desire to learn new skills and technologies.

Leadership and Volunteer Experience

United Way (2016)

 Helped to create a beautiful mosaic as well as a greater understanding and awareness for people with disabilities.

Students Today Leaders Forever (2013 – 2016)

- Learned to complete complex tasks as a team.
- Helped with community work such as tree planting, park garbage collection and carpark line drawing.
- Improved leadership skills and communication skills.

Muay Thai Club, UWRF (2012 - 2014)

- Instructed weekly training.
- Arranged monthly club officer meetings.
- Obtained instructor certificate in Thailand.

Temasek Polytechnic (2009 – 2011)

Coordinated logistical operations during events.

- Trained future logistic officers.
- Maintained monthly logistic records and reported to the club manager of the school.

Education

Master of Science in Computer Science (The Association to Advance the Collegiate School of Business (AACSB) Accredited), University of Wisconsin-River Falls (UWRF)

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Minor in Business Administration (The Association to Advance the Collegiate Schools of Business (AACSB) Accredited) (Dean's List, Beta Gamma Sigma, Senior Merit), University of Wisconsin-River Falls (UWRF)

Diploma in American Liberal Arts, American Center for Education, Singapore **Diploma in Computer Engineering**, Temasek Polytechnic, Singapore